[thudding]
-[banging]
-[grunting]
[monster screeching]
-[MAN 1] We're doomed!
-[MAN 2] It's breaking!
[all screaming]
[grunts]
Sally forth, my royal subjects
need you!
[Tatsuya growls]
[Tatsuya grunting]
[monster growls]
[Tatsuya yelling]
[monsters growling]
[Tatsuya grunts]
[Tatsuya yelling]
[grunts]
[all gasping]
[MAN 3] He's incredible.
[XYLO] This battle is over!
[NORGALLE] You are safe now.
My good people, rest easy.
We shall leave this mine
together with due haste.
And you will all be handsomely
rewarded for your service.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[FOREMAN 1] Honestly,
we didn't expect help to come.
[XYLO] I don't blame you.
We were sent
by the Holy Knights.
I need all of you men
to arm yourselves.
King Norgalle there,
he's a sacred seal specialist.
[FOREMAN 2] A King?
[NORGALLE] Down here,
without any sunlight
to power them,
sacred seals
consume energy fast.
The luminescence that is stored
within any object
is finite by nature.
As such, the sacred seal
will have a limited number
of uses.
That said, if I carve a seal,
its energy consumption
is vastly lower
than the mass-produced variety
you may have seen,
and its effectiveness
is greatly improved.
A testament to my status
as the one true king.
Now, Xylo, how long
can we keep fighting?
[XYLO] Hm.
Good question.
[MAN 1] What's that clasp?
Pardon?
[MAN 1] Oh, sorry.
I was just curious.
This thing gauges the amount
of luminescence in my body.
The light becomes dimmer
when I'm in short supply.
You're blessed
with much luminescence,
a great deal more
than the average man.
As expected of my elite guard.
I'm truly honored
by your recognition.
[XYLO] But I'm afraid we can't
hold out much longer.
The order to withdraw
came too late.
It's always us lowly workers
who are the last ones
to be informed.
Thank you.
It was kind
to share your water.
You keep it.
[gasps softly]
Hmm.
We're all grateful
for what you've done.
[XYLO] Are these
the only survivors?
I expected more.
There used to be 50 of us back
before this horrific mess began.
But then, one of my men
suddenly started hearing
a strange voice.
A voice?
That's right. And one night
while the rest of us slept,
he wandered off.
When he returned,
he had transformed
into a monster.
That's why...
we did it.
I swear we had no choice.
[NORGALLE]
Does everyone have a weapon?
The time has arrived.
Prepare for battle!
[indistinct chatter]
Tatsuya shall lead the way!
And you, I need you--
I'm well aware.
Ensuring our retreat
goes smoothly
will be disgustingly difficult.
I'll stay back
and guard the rear.
Gentlemen,
I ask that you watch
each other's backs.
Whatever we face,
I refuse to leave
even a single man behind.
[indistinct chatter]
Xylo, upon our
triumphant return,
I shall grant you the title
of commander-in-chief.
Honor and glory await you.
Thank you. I can hardly wait.
-[rumbling]
-[men exclaim]
-[MAN 1] What is that?
-[MAN 2] Oh, no.
But we haven't even tried
to leave yet!
[monsters growling]
[grunting, panting]
-[XYLO] Get up!
-[MAN 2] Uh?
Unless you wanna die,
protect yourselves!
[yells, grunts]
[monsters growling]
[grunts]
Forget the old plan.
We'll stay here
and hold the line.
Take them out!
[MAN 3] That's impossible.
We're outnumbered!
[monsters growling]
Well, damn.
Now this finally feels
like a proper punishment.
[NORGALLE] Let us decide
the order of our deaths.
You shall have the honor
of dying first, Xylo.
Greatly appreciated,
Your Majesty.
[NORGALLE] I die next,
followed by Tatsuya.
The lives of my kingdom's
servants are at stake.
Our lives are just meaningless
fodder in comparison.
[all gasp]
[monsters growling]
You're one hell of a monarch!
[indistinct chatter]
Dismissed.
Return to your post.
[HOLY KNIGHT] Right!
[Teoritta groans]
She's been that way
since her hero left.
Morose and out of sorts,
clearly no use as a weapon.
We'll go when preparations
are complete.
The Demon Lord will fall.
[monsters screeching]
[XYLO]
Patch up whoever's bleeding.
Just one sip of water each.
[groaning]
[indistinct chatter]
Try not to get too comfortable.
Get back on your feet
as soon as you're able.
[MAN 1] Please, I can't move.
-[MAN 2] My legs are throbbing.
-[MAN 3] I can't go on.
[XYLO] Complaining won't help.
Would you prefer to die?
[indistinct chatter]
[NORGALLE] Gentlemen...
I know your hearts.
You risk your lives
tearing down walls
serving as this kingdom's
lifeblood,
and do so with hardly
a word of recognition.
So I know...
fear may tempt,
but it shall never poison you.
♪
Now...
arise and fight.
[foreman grunts softly]
I suppose if you believe
in all of us,
we'll keep fighting.
Didn't say that after my speech.
[FOREMAN] About that seal etched
around your neck...
I know what it means.
You're heroes, aren't you?
That's right. It's no secret.
Assume you also know
that heroes are
the world's vilest criminals.
Whatever evil deeds
you may have committed
in your old life,
you still came to rescue us.
You didn't just write us off
as expendable.
And that's worth a lot.
Enough to inspire us to seek out
a noble way to die.
Screw that plan.
You aren't dying here,
nobly or not.
Indeed.
Your fierce devotion
to this kingdom,
the long years spent
toiling away
in dirt and sweat...
Your lives are precious.
And worth saving.
I won't let them be stolen away.
-[rumbling]
-[gasping]
[Tatsuya grunting]
Dammit. If we had a probe seal,
we would at least know
how many there are.
[men grunting]
-[MAN 1] Let's do this.
-I ain't dying just yet.
Ready? Brace!
[monsters screeching]
They're going left!
Hold them off!
-[monsters growling]
-[man whimpering]
[yelling]
[BOTH] Hmm.
[both yelling]
[monster screeching]
Good work, now keep it up!
-[XYLO] Uh?
-[Norgalle grunts]
[grunts] No matter what,
you must keep fighting!
[Tatsuya grunts]
Majesty!
-[monsters screeching]
-Die!
[men grunting]
[BOTH] Huh?
[both grunting]
-Dammit!
-[BOTH] Foreman!
-[monster screeching]
-[foreman grunts]
[foreman whimpering]
♪
[both gasp]
[panting]
I trust you shall forgive
my delayed arrival.
The Goddess of Swords, Teoritta.
I grace you with my presence!
[chuckles]
[TEORITTA]
No need to hold back.
Rejoice. You have permission
to extol my glorious strength.
[Xylo grunts]
Dear goddess, I see you have
come to bless our endeavors.
You have my sincerest thanks.
It delights me
to assist your cause.
Between my knight's skill
and my blessings,
your victory is now assured.
[NORGALLE] Brave men,
we must construct a fence.
I will engrave the swords
with sacred seals.
When I am finished,
plant them in the ground.
-[MEN] Sir!
-[Teoritta chuckles]
[XYLO] What are you doing here?
I left you
with the Holy Knights.
I slipped through their fingers.
Their vigilant eyes were
no match for my cunning.
Now, Xylo,
lavish your praise
upon my head.
Praise you? Hell no.
Whyever not? Punishment?
For arriving so belatedly?
Yet I am not to blame!
For it was you who chose
to abandon your goddess.
Truly, it was unbearable.
My errant knight plea--
Don't you listen?
I'm not going
to use your divine power
to complete this mission.
[Teoritta gasps]
[TEORITTA] I am at a loss.
How can I grant your wish
unless you give it voice?
[XYLO] I'll tell you my wish.
Stop chasing martyrdom for glory
or in service of others.
Stay alive,
even if you're useless.
[Teoritta exclaims]
[chuckles softly]
How lovely, yet your beautiful
words do not deter me one bit.
They prove you
are worthy of my sacrifice.
[Xylo gasps]
[TEORITTA] You strive
to keep me at a distance.
A desperate ploy to protect
my well-being, is it not?
You and your damn theory
can piss off!
How fortuitous that even
your most callous opinions
about me are irrelevant.
[XYLO] Are they?
I am a goddess, after all.
The whole reason I exist
is to be of use to others.
-I covet praise and exaltation.
-There. Finally got it!
[TEORITTA]
Nothing less will do!
Even if this desire
is nothing more than a symptom
of my nature,
that does not alter my wish.
To pursue a glorious life,
and noble death.
You shall find this hard
to accept.
Yet here it is, my knight.
Even you cannot stop
my heart from yearning.
[Xylo groaning softly]
-[rumbling]
-[gasps]
Another wave incoming.
Men to your posts!
Remain within the fence!
They can't get through
the ground here.
You had better stay back.
[TEORITTA] Xylo,
if you disapprove
my bent towards
self-sacrifice...
It is quite simple.
You must protect me
at all costs.
You make it sound so easy.
I suppose that's exactly
what I'll have to do.
Take this.
And this!
-There's more an...
-[high-pitched ringing]
[men screaming]
I hear it.
Is that the voice?
[men grunting, screaming]
[Norgalle grunting]
[Tatsuya grunts, yells]
[Xylo grunting]
[TEORITTA] My knight!
[XYLO] I'm fine.
[Teoritta grunts]
My powers of protection
and healing.
May they quieten the cacophony.
[Xylo grunts]
I never asked you to help me.
[Xylo grunting]
My poor knight, you are...
I'll have to
hear you out afterward.
It is here.
The source of
the Demon Lord Blight.
♪
[TEORITTA] The true battle
shall now begin.
[WOMAN] You...
Yes.
You...
I found you.
[Teoritta gasps]
[WOMAN] I found you!
[XYLO] That's it.
Demon Lord Lotus.
-[high-pitched ringing]
-[all screaming]
[screaming]
[man groaning] The voice.
I hear it.
The voice!
Stay where you are!
That thing will corrupt
your soul.
Quiet! The voice is trying
to tell me something important!
[grunting]
[XYLO] Stop it!
Damn it. Hey!
[NORGALLE] I swear.
You'll die.
How dare you seek
to lead my people astray!
Filthy thief!
You contemptible usurper!
Teoritta, leaving this fence
is a death sentence.
We'll have to support Tatsuya
from here!
[Tatsuya grunting]
Do you believe that
he can succeed alone?
He doesn't seem to be
affected by the tinnitus.
Hurry, I need you to make
more swords for me.
Inspired idea!
You should rely on me
as much as possible!
It's been a while
since I covered someone else.
[Tatsuya grunting]
Keep it up, Tatsuya!
Go and slay the Demon Lord!
[Tatsuya grunting]
[Lotus screeching]
♪
You've got this!
-Keep going!
-[Tatsuya yelling]
[Tatsuya grunts]
Need more swords!
A storm of blades!
Granted!
[Xylo grunting, yelling]
[Tatsuya grunting]
[Tatsuya yelling]
Slice it in two!
[both gasp]
That body. It was a decoy.
Xylo, look!
[monster growls]
There it is.
The core. [gasps]
A hell of a time to run out.
There it is! Go and support
the goddess and miners!
-[high-pitched ringing]
-[Xylo grunts]
Stop it! Stay back!
[knights screaming]
[grunts] What is this?
[all screaming]
[HOLY KNIGHT]
The voice is calling.
[grunting]
-[XYLO] Dammit all.
-[gasps]
[Xylo grunting]
[all screaming]
[choking]
[Norgalle grunting]
Majesty!
I will protect my people,
even if it kills me!
You shall pay.
The king has spoken,
you filthy usurper!
[Lotus screams]
[XYLO] That's it, Your Majesty!
Burn the core!
You stole my precious people,
you fiend...
[gasps, grunts]
Damn you!
[Tatsuya grunting]
-[Xylo gasps]
-Hurry! We'll cover you!
Xylo! My knight.
Put an end to it!
[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] Burn to death,
you bastard!
[grunts]
What am I supposed to do?
[Norgalle grunting]
You'll pay for this.
I swear I'll make you pay!
[grunting]
You'll see.
You shall regret this!
I demand penance in blood
for every subject
that you stole!
[shouts] I'll make you pay!
-[NORGALLE] Norgalle.
-[Norgalle gasps]
Norgalle!
Stay right where you are!
I'm coming to save you!
[Lotus screeches]
Majesty!
[grunts]
You really are
one hell of a king,
you know that?
[Lotus screams]
[gasps, pants]
[HOLY KNIGHT 1] Is it over?
[HOLY KNIGHT 2]
The heroes. They did it.
[FOREMAN]
That should stem the bleeding.
[Norgalle grunting]
[NORGALLE] This time,
did I make it?
My people...
I must protect them.
They need their king.
Right? [grunting]
[Tatsuya groans]
The deed is done,
noble knight.
[Xylo sighs]
[XYLO] Yeah.
-[indistinct chatter]
-[CHILD] Mommy!
[WOMAN] Thank goodness
you're home safe!
[GIRL] We missed you
so much, Daddy!
[indistinct chatter]
[SIENA] Rajit?
Hear, hear!
Good work, everybody.
-[Venetim gulps]
-[both grunt]
[VENETIM] Ah!
Oh! No need to worry
about the king.
What's left of him has been
sent off to the repair shop.
Though, I imagine he'll receive
a new leg from someone else.
-Maybe?
-[XYLO] I hope they at least
give him the best one
they've got.
The mad king saved
a lot of lives today,
so he deserves some reward
for his trouble.
[WOMAN 1] Heroes?
-[MAN 1] Impossible.
-[MAN 2] Aren't they criminals?
[WOMAN 2] Unbelievable.
[MAN] What really happened?
[all murmuring]
[Xylo scoffs]
[FOREMAN] Don't worry.
I'm certain they'll all
come to understand
your kindness
one of these days.
It's no big deal.
We're all used to it.
[FOREMAN] Regardless, no matter
what anyone else says,
you're the reason
we're still alive.
[XYLO] Hmm.
I owe you my life and honor.
Thanks to you,
we didn't die nobly
or otherwise.
Well, thank
His Majesty for that.
I know.
And I will someday.
But on this day,
we get to celebrate
my daughter's birthday
-as a family.
-Go on.
You have something
for him, don't you?
[GIRL] Mm-hm.
Um...
Thank you so much,
Mr. Hero.
[gasps softly]
[exclaims softly]
[TEORITTA] Ahem.
Child, take heed!
It was my blessing
that allowed him
to fight so valiantly.
I am deserving
of your accolades,
and, therefore, first in line
as his goddess.
-[parents chuckle]
-What? Goddess?
[XYLO] Enough.
Don't boss around
fellow children.
[Teoritta gasps]
"Fellow children"?
You're calling me a child?
Flagrant insolence!
I urge you to keep
such thoughts to yourself--
[XYLO] Settle down.
I appreciate the gesture,
but it doesn't suit me.
[Teoritta grunting]
-[XYLO] Teoritta.
-[gasps]
You can have it if you want.
[Teoritta exclaims softly]
[chuckles] Yes.
It is
a truly charming flower.
[scoffs] Why do kids
love flowers so much?
[Teoritta grunts]
My knight, you shall cease
describing me that way!
It's difficult to quantify
how many regulations
they've broken.
I will see to it that
they get reprimanded.
Hold it right there.
Even if they are criminals,
they still went out of their way
to save lives.
I would say they've earned
a little praise.
They're heroes!
[KIVIA] Better than
a coward waving a crest,
who never does a minute
of actual fighting himself.
[priest gasps, grunts]
[KIVIA] Xylo Forbartz...
the goddess-killer hero.
See?
I adore it,
and you can rest assured
that my knight and I shall--
[XYLO] Come. It's time to go.
[TEORITTA] Now? Surely we have
time for more adulation!
[GIRL] I wanna
talk some more, too!
-[TEORITTA] Of course!
-[Xylo sighs]